

# **LUCAS LUNELLI**

INFORMATION MANAGEMENT



## **PROFILE**

Highly **adaptable** engineer with master in Information Management and a passion for **problem solving**.

Experience in advising on business strategy using a **data-driven** approach.

Expert in all phases of **data & analytics** lifecycle.



linkedin.com/in/lucaslunelli



lucasmlunelli@gmail.com



968 469 266



### **EXPERTISE**

**Data Analysis** 

Storytelling

**Business Awareness** 

Strategic Thinking

**Business Analytics** 

Communication

**Project Management** 



# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### DATA ANALYTICS SPECIALIST | NOVO BANCO

JUL 2020 -

Responsible for developing the analytics program of Novo Banco's internal audit department.

Technologies:

PowerBI, Python, SQL.

## DATA ANALYTICS CONSULTANT | BNP PARIBAS JAN 2

JAN 2018 - JUN 2020

Activities:

Collaborated with internal clients to better understand their operational and strategic needs in terms of data analysis;

Led projects by managing key stakeholders, implementing project methodology and governance while also providing technical expertise;

Developed end-to-end Business Intelligence solutions: data gathering, data transformation, report designing, documentation and deployment.

Technologies:

Alteryx, Tableau, PowerBI, SQL, Python, GIT.

#### **BUSINESS ANALYST | QUERO-QUERO**

NOV 2015 - AUG 2017

Activities:

Developed and implemented business strategies to increase the profitability of credit card related products;

Defined requirements and managed projects for systemic improvements, regulatory changes and new features;

Prepared the annual budget and the monthly forecast for the revenue of the financial products.

Technologies:

Excel, VBA, SPSS, SQL.



# **EDUCATION**

#### NOVA INFORMATION MANAGEMENT SCHOOL

2017 - 2019

Master in Information Management

Specialization in Knowledge Management and Business Intelligence

## UNIVERSIDADE FEDERAL DO RIO GRANDE DO SUL 2010 - 2015

**Bachelor in Chemical Engineering** 

# UNIVERSITY OF NEW SOUTH WALES

2013

One-year study abroad program

Science Without Borders scholarship program. Expenses and tuition fees funded by the Brazilian government.